
🦞 OpenClaw 2026.2.18 (d17a1f3) — OpenAI-compatible, not OpenAI-dependent.

Usage: openclaw [options] [command]

Options:
  --dev             Dev profile: isolate state under ~/.openclaw-dev, default
                    gateway port 19001, and shift derived ports (browser/canvas)
  -h, --help        Display help for command
  --no-color        Disable ANSI colors
  --profile <name>  Use a named profile (isolates
                    OPENCLAW_STATE_DIR/OPENCLAW_CONFIG_PATH under
                    ~/.openclaw-<name>)
  -V, --version     output the version number

Commands:
  Hint: commands suffixed with * have subcommands. Run <command> --help for details.
  acp *             Agent Control Protocol tools
  agent             Run one agent turn via the Gateway
  agents *          Manage isolated agents (workspaces, auth, routing)
  approvals *       Manage exec approvals (gateway or node host)
  browser *         Manage OpenClaw's dedicated browser (Chrome/Chromium)
  channels *        Manage connected chat channels (Telegram, Discord, etc.)
  clawbot *         Legacy clawbot command aliases
  completion        Generate shell completion script
  config *          Non-interactive config helpers (get/set/unset). Default:
                    starts setup wizard.
  configure         Interactive setup wizard for credentials, channels, gateway,
                    and agent defaults
  cron *            Manage cron jobs via the Gateway scheduler
  daemon *          Gateway service (legacy alias)
  dashboard         Open the Control UI with your current token
  devices *         Device pairing + token management
  directory *       Lookup contact and group IDs (self, peers, groups) for
                    supported chat channels
  dns *             DNS helpers for wide-area discovery (Tailscale + CoreDNS)
  docs              Search the live OpenClaw docs
  doctor            Health checks + quick fixes for the gateway and channels
  gateway *         Run, inspect, and query the WebSocket Gateway
  health            Fetch health from the running gateway
  help              Display help for command
  hooks *           Manage internal agent hooks
  logs              Tail gateway file logs via RPC
  memory *          Search and reindex memory files
  message *         Send, read, and manage messages
  models *          Discover, scan, and configure models
  node *            Run and manage the headless node host service
  nodes *           Manage gateway-owned node pairing and node commands
  onboard           Interactive onboarding wizard for gateway, workspace, and
                    skills
  pairing *         Secure DM pairing (approve inbound requests)
  plugins *         Manage OpenClaw plugins and extensions
  qr                Generate iOS pairing QR/setup code
  reset             Reset local config/state (keeps the CLI installed)
  sandbox *         Manage sandbox containers for agent isolation
  security *        Security tools and local config audits
  sessions          List stored conversation sessions
  setup             Initialize local config and agent workspace
  skills *          List and inspect available skills
  status            Show channel health and recent session recipients
  system *          System events, heartbeat, and presence
  tui               Open a terminal UI connected to the Gateway
  uninstall         Uninstall the gateway service + local data (CLI remains)
  update *          Update OpenClaw and inspect update channel status
  webhooks *        Webhook helpers and integrations

Examples:
  openclaw models --help
    Show detailed help for the models command.
  openclaw channels login --verbose
    Link personal WhatsApp Web and show QR + connection logs.
  openclaw message send --target +15555550123 --message "Hi" --json
    Send via your web session and print JSON result.
  openclaw gateway --port 18789
    Run the WebSocket Gateway locally.
  openclaw --dev gateway
    Run a dev Gateway (isolated state/config) on ws://127.0.0.1:19001.
  openclaw gateway --force
    Kill anything bound to the default gateway port, then start it.
  openclaw gateway ...
    Gateway control via WebSocket.
  openclaw agent --to +15555550123 --message "Run summary" --deliver
    Talk directly to the agent using the Gateway; optionally send the WhatsApp reply.
  openclaw message send --channel telegram --target @mychat --message "Hi"
    Send via your Telegram bot.

Docs: https://docs.openclaw.ai/cli

